KIM MOON

Naperville, IL 60564

4343 Dairymans Circle Email: kimmoon@uic.edu Home: 630-536-8906 Mobile: 269-208-7988

CAREER SUMMARY

Senior brand marketer leverages 13 years of corporate experience in academia; solid 10 years of teaching experience at various colleges. Breadth of professional background spans across marketing mix with Fortune 200 companies in various industries: health & beauty, appliances, home care, financial services, medical and consumer packaged foods.

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS-CHICAGO (August 2008-Present)

Chicago, IL

Research-based institution that serves diverse body of 3,000 business students

Lecturer, College of Business Administration

- Instructing approximately 100 undergraduate and graduate students; courses include Consumer Behavior, B2B Marketing, Marketing Management and International Marketing
- ·Overseeing 3 graduate and undergraduate level Independent Studies
- Serving as Graduate Advisor and occasional panelist for Graduate Marketing Association (G.M.A.R.K.)

LAKE MICHIGAN COLLEGE (September 2008-Present)

Benton Harbor, MI

Two-year community college that serves over 177k residents across four campuses

Online Adjunct Instructor-Advertising & Marketing Principles

- · Conducting weekly discussion forums on relevant topic areas across the marketing mix
- · Instructing students on case methodology through exams and research papers

TRITON COLLEGE (January 2008-May 2008)

River Grove, IL

Comprehensive community college that serves over 17k students

Marketing Adjunct Instructor

- ·Used case methodology to teach the fundamentals of marketing principles to 22 students
- · Developed additional marketing projects and assignments to enhance the theoretical learning experience

LAKE MICHIGAN COLLEGE (January 2002-May 2006)

Benton Harbor, MI

Two-year community college that serves over 177k residents across four campuses

Marketing Adjunct Instructor

- · Established new course outcomes with the addition of a marketing plan for final project
- ·Counseled and mentored students in need of academic and career advice

AREAS OF EXPERTISE & INTEREST

Principles of Marketing • Advertising & Promotions • Strategic Marketing • Consumer Behavior Communications • Sales • Marketing Management • Product Development • B2B Marketing International Marketing • Ethnic Marketing

International Marketing . Editic Marketing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WHIRLPOOL CORPORATION (April 2000-July 2006)

Benton Harbor, MI

#1 global marketer of home appliances with annual revenues of \$20 billion

Senior Manager, Strategic Competencies

- Developed & executed global strategy for Consumer Excellence, one of three core competencies identified to close \$7 billion customer loyalty gap
- ·Submitted recommendations for the redesign of Knowledge Management site to support 80k employee base

Global Brand Manager, Brand Excellence

- Built global infrastructure to develop skill-sets of 400 managers within brand organization; influenced 60 stakeholders and decision-makers to achieve 70% participation rate in year one
- · Led design & deployment of new marketing curricula to establish consistency across Asia, Latin America and Europe

Innovation Consultant, North America Region

- · Focused on developing \$1.5 million in new business opportunities across product and service dimensions
- · Constructed three test markets for new Pla® brand, which was developed exclusively for Best Buy®

Brand Manager, Whirlpool Dishwashers

- · Managed P&L by analyzing business performance of the \$250 million Whirlpool dishwasher brand
- Drove record market share to 19 points by successfully launching new dishwasher product line
- · Managed Procter & Gamble® strategic partnership to drive sales and new product innovations

AMERICAN EXPRESS TRAVEL-RELATED SERVICES (April 1999-March 2000)

New York, NY

Leading global financial services company with revenues of \$31 billion

Manager, Optima® Portfolio

- Developed, tested and executed quarterly direct-mail campaigns for existing card holders to generate \$1 billion in profitable revenue
- · Conducted historical analysis of \$5 billion Optima® direct-mail campaigns; implemented recommendations to target Membership Rewards® segment

S.C. JOHNSON WAX & SON, INC (August 1996-January 1999)

Leading consumer packaged goods company with revenues in excess of \$6 billion

Racine, WI

- Associate Brand Manager, Glade® Candles
- Managed P&L for \$25 million Glade® votive candle business
 Managed national T.V. and Print campaign budgets and strategic revisions
- Led launch of line-extension and packaging restage of 2nd largest candle segment

Associate Brand Manager, Skintimate® Shave Gel for Women

- Developed and executed incremental promotion to successfully defend business against top competitor
- · Gained new warehouse club distribution by creating 'special-pack'; resulted in gross sales of \$5 million
- · Increased penetration by 25% through developing and implementing sampling strategy

Assistant Brand Manager, Skintimate® Shave Gel for Women

- ·Oversaw and executed promotions for base business of \$60 million Skintimate® brand
- · Conducted qualitative research in three consumer markets to develop strategy for targeting Latina women
- · Collaborated with Schick® brand to develop co-branded 'special-pack' promotions

ABBOTT LABORATORIES, DIAGNOSTICS DIVISION (January 1993-August 1994)

Lincolnshire, IL

Broad-based health care company with \$25 billion in annual revenues

Area Account Manager, Wisconsin

- · Sold high-end medical testing equipment to hospitals and doctor's offices
- ·Recognized and rewarded for selling first hematology analyzer in district sales contest

THE PILLSBURY COMPANY-GENERAL MILLS (February 1991-January 1993)

Buffalo, Grove, IL

Leading brand in \$1.6 billion refrigerated dough category

Sales Representative

- · Managed sales territory of 40 grocery outlets; sold six brands across hundreds of skus
- Developed regional targeted-marketing opportunity; proposal was considered for the following fiscal year

EDUCATION

C.A.U.

Atlanta, GA

GRADUATE SCHOOL OF BUSINESS (1994-1996)

M.B.A. in Marketing

Union Pacific Scholarship Recipient-G.P.A. 3.5/4.0

DEPAUL UNIVERSITY (1986-1990)

Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Science in Marketing/Minor in Communications Track & Field Scholarship Recipient

AFFILIATIONS

Illinois Runs, Running Club Safe Shelter, Past Officer & Board Member Badger State Games Gold Medalist, Power-lifting